

"Success is the sum of small efforts repeated day in and day out." - Robert Collier

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

My passion began many years ago with web design and evolved into a curiosity for how to "build stuff". I love being immersed in the programming world and am seeking a Web Developer opportunity. I am dedicated to learning my craft and would love to contribute to a team while building upon my current skill set.

Skills include:

Full-Stack Web Development, Object-Oriented Programming / Test Driven Development / Digital Project Management / Online Marketing Collateral / Graphic Design

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Ruby, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript

Frameworks & Tools: Ruby on Rails, jQuery, PostgresSQL, Heroku, AWS, Twitter Bootstrap, Git / Github, WordPress, Middleman, Photoshop

EDUCATION

Syracuse University, Syracuse, NY, 2003-2007 Martin J. Whitman School of Management Bachelor of Science; Entrepreneurship & Emerging Enterprises Dean's List

WORK EXPERIENCE

Biz Dev Now, Elkins Park, PA / Remote, March 2014 - January 2016

Web Developer / Digital Project manager

Managed and developed WordPress websites and marketing for small and medium-sized businesses.

- Customized WordPress themes with hand-coded HTML5 & CSS3
- Converted PSD and wireframes to HTML5 & CSS3
- Designed UI interfaces with Balsamiq wireframing tool
- Created web banners, ads, flyers and business cards with Photoshop
- Optimized client sites for speed and used on-site SEO best practices
- Set-up email marketing campaigns and designed newsletters in Aweber
- · Sourced and hired additional freelance web developers, graphic designers and content writers

SmartsiteMovement, Aug 2012 - Sep 2014

Founder

Created custom standalone mobile website for small businesses.

- Transferred design and content from desktop site into a mobile-friendly version
- Set-up mobile coupon and loyalty programs
- · Client acquisition, maintenance and training

Progressive Business Publications, Malvern, PA, Feb 2011 - Sep 2012

Market Analyst

- Customized HTML landing pages and optimized conversation using A/B testing
- Managed online lead generation campaigns for Fortune 500 to mid-sized companies
- Revised marketing copy for struggling email marketing campaigns to improve lead generation results

FedSources, Washington, DC Metro, 2010 - 2011

Market Intelligence Analyst

Tracked and analyzed federal government contract opportunities released by U.S. Navy agencies; Conducted in-depth internet and primary research for clients; Built professional relationships with Navy Contracting Officers; Attended industry conferences and published reports for company website.

Help Unlimited Temps & Office Team, Washington, DC Metro, 2008 - 2009

Administrative Assistant

Temp Assignments:

DC Housing Finance Agency

Provided assistance to public regarding real estate buyer program and admin support to agency.

Giuliani Associates Architects Inc.

Data entry, AP/AR, payroll assistance, project folder maintenance.

ComputerTraining.com, Newark, DE, 2007 - 2008

Assistant Director of Admissions

Conducted education sales for Microsoft Certification Program; Managed large database of potential student leads and schedule campus visits for Director of Admissions; Provided solid follow-up with potential students. Met and exceeded student enrollment goals.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Web Development, Algorithm, and Data Structures Foundations - Firehose Project, June - Oct 2015

An intensive 15-week program in which I studied to become a web developer / programmer. I learned how to develop web applications, break down complex problems into more manageable pieces and many tools of the trade.

- Learned how to build-out CRUD Rails apps following standard Rails conventions (without scaffolding), involving mailers, validations, image uploading on AWS S3 and nested RESTful routes
- Implemented tests using MiniTest's Test::Unit Syntax for both unit and functional tests
- Learned front-end development fundamentals and implemented responsive design in web applications